

SAMUEL FERNANDO PANJAITAN, S.KOM.

Padangsidimpuan, 25 May 1999 23 years old – Single – Christian Height 179 cm; Weight 55 kg



CONTACT: +62 822 7767 3747

samuelfrnando@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/samuelfp

Inspeksi Pam Street No. 6, West Cakung, East Jakarta 13910

Work Experiences

IT Business Analyst

PT. Uniair Indotama Cargo (Dimerco) | 16 November 2021 – 18 November 2022

- Worked closely with product owners, and developers to ensure that our products/ projects (Store2Go, WMS, AICE, SEB) are developed in accordance with the company's roadmap (BRD, FSD and UAT).
- Analyzed systems and mapped business processes to identify gaps and potential for improvements.
- Worked to fully understand the customer data and ensured that the data was utilized to make advantageous changes.
- Manage Master Data and presenting precise and structured reports.
- Monitor & operate WMS system (eComm+) and Customs PLB Inventory.
- Processing BC 16/BC 28 Lazada and Importir.org data into BC documents.
- Test the product (Store2Go, AICE app) and identify any bugs or errors.
- Create required documents, drafts, with standard QA procedure.
- Ensure that the products and applications designed are of good quality.

IT Support Technician

PT. Uniair Indotama Cargo (Dimerco) | 16 November 2021 – 18 November 2022

- Provided complete IT technical support services and assisted global management teams to ensure efficient business processes.
- Conduct Proof of Concept (POC) on Access Point vendors (ARUBA, UBIQUITI, SUNDRAY, RUCKUS) to be used at Uniair PLB.
- Monitoring Mikrotik network (Winbox) and data cables.
- Handle implementation, monitor, and maintenance project related with Cisco Networking Product (ASR9K with IOS-XR using secureCRT).
- Design and implement new network solutions or improve existing networks (include design documentation and migration plan).
- Update the operating system or applications regularly, Perform data Backup, Repairing damaged user computers and other hardwares.
- Create PR/PO for employee support equipment (hardware, software).

Licenses and Certifications

- EF SET English Certificate 82/100 (C2 Proficient) (29 December 2021).
- Dicoding: Building a Mobile Backend Using Kotlin (17 September 2020).
- UI/UX Research in App Development (18 July 2020).
- RH 124: Red Hat Enterprise Linux System Administration I (16 January 2020).
- Alcatel-Lucent Enterprise Geek Battle Scholarship 2019 Basic Programming (18 November 2019).

Summary

I am a Bachelor of Computer: Informatics Engineering. I am 23 years old. My concentration in college is mobile and web. I am equipped with software programming education and can work in the IT field, related to data processing. My most recent experience is working as an IT Business Analyst as well as IT Support Technician. This makes me more trained to do multitasking.

Education

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER: INFORMATICS ENGINEERING - STMIK MIKROSKIL MEDAN (11 September 2017 - 25 July 2021). **GPA** 3.47 / 4.00

Achievement

The 3rd Rank in Competition Information Technology Mobile at STMIK Mikroskil Medan (11 January 2020).

Research Experience

MEDANHUB: Mobile-Based Information Retrieval System Implementation on Society Reports Application in Medan City with Elasticsearch (13 August 2020 - 25 July 2021).

Skills

- Administration (Microsoft Office).
- UI, Flowchart & UML Design (Figma, Adobe XD, Visio, Lucidchart).
- IT Networking (Cisco Packet Tracer, Wireshark, Mikrotik Winbox, sCRT).
- Data Analysis (Postman, ELK).
- Web Design (HTML, CSS, JS).
- Programming (C#, Python, Kotlin).